Graham Alexander Noblit, Ph.D.

747-466-0574 · GrahamNoblit@pm.me · www.linkedin.com/in/graham-noblit/

Adaptable & curious Senior Data Scientist (6+ years exp.) with expertise in statistics, machine learning, and artificial intelligence. Excels in mentorship & leadership roles and at designing & managing collaborative and solo projects.

SKILLS

Engineering: Python, R, Julia, SQL, Linux, Git, Docker

Domain: Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence: Generative AI, Transformers, and Large Language

Models; Statistical Inference (Regression) and Econometrics; Causal Inference and Experiment Design (A/B Testing); Natural Language Processing (NLP); Optimization; Data Visualization

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Children's Hospital: Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

Senior Data Scientist

September 2023 – Present

- Implement machine learning and statistical pipelines for clinical research and practice
- Supervise team of data scientists: determining team's project involvement and defining project objectives and plans of completion; develop team skills by providing tutorials on recent advances in machine learning and AI
- Improve clinical note classification by 35% designing large language model/GenAl pipelines for information extraction, self-supervised training, semantic-search/vector databases, LLM querying, & knowledge distillation
- Achieve a 10% reduction in experiment costs by implementing machine learning & Bayesian methods to salvage datasets
- Deliver recommendations on large language models/generative AI to audience of over 100 of administrators, researchers, and clinicians; talk received highest rating in history of speaker series
- Audit genomics analysis pipeline, correcting errors and redefining future project-scope & data-collection

Schwartz Reisman Inst. for Technology & Society; Vector Inst. for Artificial Intelligence

Toronto, ON

Research Scientist

- September 2022 September 2023
- Designed game-theoretic models and computational simulations for multi-agent reinforcement learning
 Led weekly meetings of 15 people, planning and developing themes and speakers for multi-disciplinary and developing themes.
- Led weekly meetings of 15 people, planning and developing themes and speakers for multi-disciplinary artificial intelligence conference (100+ attendees); mentored a Ph.D. student

Independent Research Consultant

August 2019 – September 2023

- DeepMind (AI): Provided disciplinary expertise, co-designing novel reinforcement learning algorithm
- University of Chicago School of Business: Scraped and created datasets; performed statistical analyses (mixed models regression and spatial regressions) included in scientific publications
- Rare (global nonprofit): Devised research and data collection procedures for project on fishery sustainability and behavioral change in the Brazilian Amazon

Harvard University

Cambridge, MA

Doctoral Researcher

August 2016 – May 2022

- Produced three scientific articles explaining human cultural, behavioral, and economic outcomes using spatial regression, causal inference, linear and non-linear dimensionality reduction, and game-theoretic optimization
- Scraped, cleaned, and merged four spatial and non-spatial, large and small, datasets using climatic, agricultural, economic, and survey data
- Presented results to technical & non-technical audiences (~ 5-50) including a top international conference

Teaching Fellow

August 2018 – July 2021

- Statistics, Head Teaching Fellow: supervised teams of 5-9 teaching assistants and led classes of 20+
- Taught data-science & R: hypothesis testing, model selection, and interpreting & presenting results

EDUCATION